Hello! It's me, Ashley
こんにちわ！　アシュリーです。
Today we are discussing CLASSIFIERS..."CL"
今日は、「クラシファイヤー」について説明します。
ASL uses a variety of techniques to show people, places, objects, food, and actions
ASLは、物や動詞など、あらゆるテクニックで表現します。
Everything can be conveyed using our bodies
また、身体を使って表現する事もできます。
Today, we will practice classifiers using different handshapes!
今日は、一緒に手で形...
Using A hand-shape in an example...
Ａという指文字で例を作ってみよう...
While I was driving, I saw houses along the left and right side of the road. (showing location of houses)
運転している時に、道路の両沿いで並ぶ家を眺めていました。
(家の位置を表現)
Another example...
他の例は...
There were cups set around the table.
(showing location of cups on table)
テーブル上で置かれたカップがあります。
(テーブル上のカップの位置を表現)
(a floor)
(床)
(a ceiling)
(天井)
(a wall)
(壁)
(a type of shelving unit)
(ダンス)﻿
(riding a surfboard on the waves of the ocean)
(波の上のサーファー)
(riding a skateboard down the street)
(通路上のスケートボード)
(picking up a stack of books from a table)
(テーブル上で重ねている本を持ち上げて)
(pictures hanging on a wall)
(壁に掛かっている絵)
(showing height of tall person/short person)
(背の高い人/背の低い人)
(a house)
(家)
(a box)
(箱)
(riding a horse)
(乗馬)
(riding a bicycle)
(自転車に乗る)
(a bowl, a smaller bowl, a larger bowl)
(ボウル、小鉢、大鉢)
(washing your hands in a sink)
(流し台で手を洗う)
(eyelids struggling to stay open)
(開くように保とうと努力するまぶた)
(driving down a bumpy road)
(でこぼこ道を走る)
(a pregnant belly)
(太っている腹)
(an enhanced bust) (a smaller bust)
(大きな胸)(小さな胸)
(the movement of an animal's ears)
(動物の耳の動き)
(a long stretch of road)
(はるかに長い道)
(the sharp corners of a table)
(テーブルの角)
(a bookshelf)
(書棚)
(the roof of a house)
(家の屋根)
(the pipes of a toilet)
(トイレのパイプ)
(bamboo)
(竹)
(drinking from a cup)
(カップで飲む)
(a large tree trunk) (a smaller tree trunk)
(太い幹)(細い幹)
(showing biceps, abdominal muscles)
(二頭筋、腹筋)
(a thick blanket)
(厚い毛布)
(a thick jacket)
(厚いジャケット)
(a thick stack of paperwork)
(書類がたまっている)
(heavy snowfall)
(大雪)
(binoculars) (telescope)
(双眼鏡)(望遠鏡)
(revving up a motorcycle, riding off into the wind)
(オートバイに乗ってアクセルを回しながら風を受ける)
(a room full of people)
(満室)
(a bouquet of flowers)
(花束)
(reading an interesting article in the newspaper)
(新聞の各記事を読む)
(a house in the middle of the forest)
(森林に囲まれた家)
(a tent nestled in the midst of the mountains)
(山谷にあるテント)
(an officer's badge)
(警察官のバッジ)
(shocked/amazed)
(衝撃を受けた/驚嘆した)
(the nose of a clown)
(ピエロの鼻)
(a ball)
(ボール)
(showing teeth)
(歯)
(showing thickness of a pizza pie)
(ピザの厚さ)
(showing the shape of the moon)
(月)
(showing pieces of food)
(小さな食物)
(a small bottle of perfume)
(芳香の小ビン)
(a thin jacket)
(薄いジャケット)
(a thin blanket)
(薄い毛布)
(a flimsy pillow)
(薄い枕)
(a light snowfall)
(小雪)
(a person falling through thin ice)
(薄い氷で落ちる)
Those are a few handshape classifiers used in ASL...
ここで紹介したASLのクラシファイヤーは、多くある例の一部です...
次回では、他の例を紹介します！﻿ More videos with more to come!